





Senior Engineer - Business seeking roles in Technical Analysis, Project Management, Network Troubleshooting, Incident Management, Change Management, Application Support, Client Management

Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Sc [Computers]

Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Designation: Lead Engineer

Current Company: Valeo Service India

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Madurai Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Team Lead/Tech Lead

Industry: Industrial Products/Heavy Machinery

Key Skills: Senior Engineer - Business, Team Lead/Tech Lead, Technical Analysis, Project Management, Network Troubleshooting, Incident Management, Change Management, Application Support, Client Management, Security Management, Tally, PHP, SQL, Java, C, C++

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 23-Jan-21 Last Modified: 23-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Jump to Section | Work Experience | Education | 11 Ski

Summary

Young, energetic result oriented professional with more than 8 years of experience in ITIS. Stabilizing the project from pilot phase. Handling escalated tickets and giving support to the customers from various parts of the world. Deep understanding of technology with focus on delivering business solutions; Persuasive communicator with exceptional relationship management skills with ability to relate to people at any level of business and management; highly ethical, trustworthy and discreet.

Work Experience

Valeo Service India as Lead Engineer Oct 2020 to Till Date

GISOCC

Valeo India Private Limited as SENIOR ENGINEER-BUSINESS

Dec 2015 to Oct 2020

Project Name: Access Management/Transition/Service Delivery Monitoring
Desc: Valeo India is an prominent automobile company with its origin at France.as a business engineer, the role is to
manage users requesting access to corporate finance applications.

Key Deliverables:

Incident / Change Management/User Management

- * Have had to opportunity to travel onsite (Paris , France) to initiate the project.
- * Manage users Globally (28 Countries)
- * Ensuring that all the tickets are resolved within SLA
- * coordinating in between new JV POC and Valeo for smooth creation of user access
- * Perform user management and user cleaning activities to ensure data and application security and to avoid licensing issues.
- * coordinating changes for ITSM application with admin team

Transition:

- * Have been an active transition Manager for Project Transition of Service delivery from One service Provider to Other
- * Have been a co-coordinator between two service providers & Valeo to ensure smooth Transition of activity
- * Have ensured for effective transition of activities-Ensured that transition activity is carried out as per the plan and any changes are properly tracked ,Have ensured to provide the correct POC's for Access and other supporting requirements for the new Service provider to have a smooth start of Service.
- * Have ensured that all activities are transitioned an tracked up to closure
- * Have taken care of after Transition activities for the new service providers stabilization
- * Have effectively tracked down the transition status until closure of activities
- * Being the POC for Service Provider at India for after transition activity

Service delivery monitoring :

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

- * Have been successfully able to co-ordinate service delivery status between one of the Reputated Service Providers in Market and Valeo.
- * Have to responsibility to track and monitor the services Delivered
- * Ensure that all the services delivered are as per the SOW with the Service provider.
- Cascade the Escalations, If any, to the Service Provider based on the defined escalation Matrix
- * Be a point of contact for the service provider in case if they have any clarifications-Discussion with the Top

Management for Clarifications and drive to define a solution

- * Provide suggestions and Improvement Proposals to the team as and when required
- * Co-ordinate and act as a bridge between the Service Provider and Valeo to address concerns from Both sides

Cognizant Technology Solutions as Senior Systems Executive Jun 2012 to Dec 2015

Key Deliverables:

- * Monitoring servers and working on the alerts raised.
- * Troubleshooting network equipment's taking remote if necessary.
- * Manipulating the severity of the issue and assigning the tickets to

Concerned vendor with appropriate priority.

* Triage incidents and initiate bridge during critical situations.

Project Name: Liberty Mutual Insurance - Incident management /Application support /Change Management Project Description: Liberty Mutual is one the top insurance companies in USAAs an application support team, we support the online/Mobile applications and other supporting applications used by the business. The team is primarily responsible to make sure the applications are available for use in production

Key Deliverables:

- * Monitoring applications in both production and non-production environments and working on the alerts raised.
- * Follow up the incidents and ensured that it is resolved within the SLA
- * Ensure that all the priority notifications are sent and documented based on the existing ITIL process
- * Based on the ITIL process, track ticket until RCAis done for priority tickets and co-ordinate with change management team.
- * Triage incidents and initiate bridge during critical situations.
- * Notify the clients and stakeholders regarding any critical situation along with business impact and root cause.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from KAMARAJAR UNIVERSITY in 2012

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Windows XP, Windows 7		
MS word, MS excel, MS power point		
C & C++, Java		
PHP, Tally 9, ASP.NET		
SQL, ORACLE		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	
Tamil	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
French	Beginner			✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved @ 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.